Kyle Romero

kgromero@gmail.com (281) 857-9006 https://kgromero.us

Hello! My name is Kyle Romero. I am a softw are development manager, with full-stack senior softw are development experience, living in Houston, Texas. I have a Bachelor's Degree in Computer Engineering from Texas Tech University, and have worked in the IT field since 2007 in softw are engineering. Currently, I am a manager of operations technology, and previously was a team lead and senior developer at Worldwide Machinery, and a technical lead at HP I have extensive knowledge of all aspects of a successful software project, and have used many different technologies and methodologies over the years.

Linkedin kyleromero Github romero927

SKILLS

LANGUAGES	C#, VB.NET, ASP.NET, Typescript, ES5, ES2015
DATABASES	MSSQL
SCRIPTING	Bash, Pow ershell (Novice)
FRAMEWORKS	.NET 4.5, .NET 3.5, .NET 2.0, ASP.NET MVC WebAPI, Angular, React, React-Router, Redux, Redux-Thunk, Webpack, Babel, SuperAgent, SCSS, Bootstrap, JQuery
DEVELOPMENT TOOLS	GIT (Bitbucket, GitKraken / Bash), VSTS, SVN (TortoiseSVN), Visual Studio 2015, Visual Studio Code, SSMS, TeamCity, JIRA, Trello, VSTS, Windows 10/8.1/7, Linux (Ubuntu), MacOS Sierra, IIS, Node + NPM / YARN + Express + PM2, NGINX Reverse Proxy, Docker (Novice), Azure, Digital Ocean, LucidCharts
FORMER PROFICIENCIES	Java, C (Microcontroller), C++, Matlab, Verilog / VHDL, Perl

EXPERIENCE

InfraSource, A Quanta Services Company

Operations Technology Manager Oct 2017 - Present

Construction and Professional Services (Energy Sector)

- Managing a team of internal and outsourced developers
- Develop modern web application using Angular, HTML5, and CSS3; hosted on IIS
- Develop RESTful API using ASP.NET MVC WebAPI
- Manage DevOps, CICD, and PM processes using VSTS
- Server administration (Windows Servers)
- Azure Administration
- Architect and explore new technology solutions

Worldwide Machinery

Team Lead / Senior Software Developer Apr 2016 - Oct 2017

Heavy Machinery Rental and Sales Company

- Manage project w orkflow using Agile Scrum methodology
- Manage junior developers' w orkloads
- Develop modern ASP.NET MVC WebAPI
- Develop modern Mobile-first Web Application using React, Redux, Typescript (ES6), Node.js + Express + NPM, Babel, Webpack, and SASS
- Maintain legacy ERP application using .NET Winforms (C#, MS SQL)
- Implement and Maintain Project and DevOps Processes using: JIRA, Bitbucket (GIT), TeamCity, Trello, Slack, Lucidcharts
- Proactively identify process improvements, as well as project opportunities
- Maintain / troubleshoot hardware infrastructure as needed (Windows / Ubuntu Servers)

HP Inc.

Technical Lead (IT Developer / Engineer III) Dec 2014 - Feb 2016

Consumer IT Products

- Led development team w orking on enterprise level product quality / escalation management tool.
- Helped manage both onshore and offshore, full time and contingent developers.
- Helped to define and improve processes used on project, including development of a customized disciplined agile methodology and setting project timelines.
- Administered Team Foundation Server (source and requirements).
- Managed quality control and workloads for developers on project.
- Managed release process for tool.
- Worked with business to define requirements and develop architecture for project.
- Familiar with all aspects of project, from both technical and business standpoints.
- While w orking on .NET Applications, received exposure to Big Data technologies, such as Hadoop and HP Vertica, as well as Dashboarding Technologies, such as Qlikview and Tableau.
- During the year 2015, led team to successfully complete clone of our systems to be used on both sides of HP after the company split into two.

HP Inc.

Software Developer (IT Developer / Engineer II) Nov 2011 - Dec 2014

- Worked on ASP.NET Web applications incorporating a 3-Tier approach.
- Did w ork on all three tiers (MS SQL Database, VB.NET Middle tier object libraries, and ASP.NET + jQueryUl frontend).

- Project w as managed using Agile Scrum methodology (Received Certified Scrum Master certification 2012).
- Source control system w as Team Foundation Server.

X-Fab Texas, Inc.

Software / Systems Engineer Dec 2009 - Nov 2011

Pure-play Semiconductor Foundry

- Development of ASP.NET/C# Web applications to serve as frontends for MSSQL databases.
- Developed .NET Web / Console / Winforms Applications.
- Involved in Database Design. Administered Windows and Linux servers.
- Designed Shell / Batch scripts. Developed C++ console applications.
- Deployed machine monitoring system. Developed Inventory tracking system.
- Deployed Documentation system to sites globally.

X-Fab Texas, Inc.

IT Intern May 2007 - Dec 2009

Internship between TTU EE Department and X-Fab, Texas

■ Developed various internal softw are projects, including statistical analysis programs, format conversion softw are, and .NET web applications.

EDUCATION

Texas Tech University

Aug 2005 - Dec 2009

Bachelor of Science - Computer Engineering GPA: 2.944

REFERENCES

— Available Upon Request